Guide to the China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Papers of Individuals: H - M, Series II
  - Lewis, Neil and Alice
    - Writings and notes, including "Looking Forward to the Foochow Union General Hospital", "Drawbacks and Advantages of Being a Missionary", "Health of Missionaries" (Box 361, Folder 8)
    - Mission reports, including re. Ingtai medical situation, Kukliang mission meeting, report to Prudential Committee, 1929-1932 (Box 361, Folder 9)
    - Reports of Native Hospital, Diong-loh, Pagoda Hospital, 1918-1929 (Box 361, Folder 10)
    - Reports, including re. ABCFM mission Ing Hok, Foochow Missionary Hospital, Chinese Medical Association prayer cycle, constitution and by-laws of Foochow Mission, 1915-1930 (Box 361, Folder 11-12)
    - Two issues of The Missionary Herald, 1927 (Box 362, Folder 13)
    - Issues of Foochow Messenger, 1914-1931 (Box 362, Folder 14-16)
    - Foochow Union Medical College syllabus, appeal; prospectus of the Foochow Medical School; constitution and by-laws of Kuliang Sanitarium, 1924, n.d. (Box 362, Folder 17)
    - Biographical documentation and photographs of Lewises (Box 362, Folder 18)
    - Collected material including regarding Euclid Avenue Congregational Church, Oberlin College, map, printouts re. diseases (Box 362, Folder 19-21)
    - Photographs, including China scenes, ABCFM commissioning certificates (Box OV6)
    - Newspaper clippings, including re. political disruption in Foochow area, 1926-1927 (Box 380, Folder 6)
    - Article by Robert E. Lewis, "The Missionary Revolution" in The Christian Century (1928); 1928 report of Dr. and Mrs. Neil H. Lewis, "The Evacuation of Kuling" by E. D. Kellogg, miscellaneous collected material, 1928, no date (Box 380, Folder 7)
  - Lewis, Wilson Seeley
    Biog. info: MEFB Peking, Foochow (L.1916-L.1921)
    - Correspondence to friend, 1908 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Picture postcard of W.S. Lewis (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Clippings concerning W.S. Lewis, 1921 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material re. WSL's funeral: "In Memoriam Wilson Seeley Lewis, 1921 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material (Brochure): The Lewis Memorial Institutional Church at Chungking, West China - To Perpetuate the memory and ministry of Bishop Wilson Seeley Lewis and to help make A Christian China (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Leynse, James P.
    Biog. info: PN Peking (L.1923-L.1940)
    - Circular letters from Peking, 1929-1946 (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - Typescript report from Peking, 1929-1933 (Box 115, Folder 7)
    - Report, Presbyterian Mission, Peking; Program for Evangelistic Work; Bibliography, literature of Chou Ch'in Dynasties; Notes on inflation in China (Box 115, Folder 8)
    - Typescript Material re. various reports, stories, etc., 1930-1933 (Box 115, Folder 9-10)
    - Typed notes on Missions, Evangelical Work, Peking (Box 115, Folder 11)
    - Elec. cop. ms by James P. Leynse: "Beauty for Ashes" (1929-1946, n.d.) (Box 116, Folder 1-5)
  - Libby, Walter and Lucile
    Biog. info: MEFB Wuhu, Nanchang (1916-1940)
    - Correspondence: Circular letters of Libbys, 1931-1983; letters to children, 1937-1960; letters to family and friends, circular letters of others (Box 41)
    - Writings of Lucile and Walter Libby, and Don Johnston (Box 41)
    - Biographical information: autobiography of WL; biographical writing re. WL, tributes and obituaries following his untimely death in 1940; material re. LL (Box 41)
    - Collected Material: newsclippings, material re. Nanchang General Hospital, photographs (Box 41)
  - Lind, Jenny
    Biog. info: MEFB Kiukiang (1924-1942, 1948-1951)
    - Correspondence (General), 1928-1976 (Box 117, Folder 1-33)
    - Photographs incl. Kiukiang's refugee camps (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (General), 1925-1964 (Box 118, Folder 2-13)
    - Correspondence (Mimeographed) to family and friends, 1930-1950 (Box 118, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence to family, 1927-1942 (Box 118, Folder 15)
    - Typescript Material: "After the Declaration of War", "A Prayer for Everyday", "A New Thing under the Sun", etc., 1927-1946 (Box 118, Folder 16)
    - Holograph ms. written by Jenny Lind (Box 118, Folder 17)
    - Misc. Printed Material incl. "The Rose of Sharon", "Christianity lives on in China", "FActs in Brief Concerning China's Floods of 1931", etc., 1931-1944 (Box 118, Folder 18-19)
    - Chinese language material (Box 118, Folder 20)
    - Writings, passport, Japanese Military permission sheet for travel on the Yangtze River (Box 118, Folder 21)
    - Typescript Material related to Knowles Bible Training School, 1922-1933 (Box 118, Folder 22)
    - Printed Material: Kuliang Directory, 1934 (Box 118, Folder 23)
    - Diary; Biographical Sketch, 1939 (Box 118, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1930-1966 (Box 118, Folder 25)
    - Collected material (Box OV4)
  - Lindholm, Paul R. and Clara
    The Lindholms were American Presbyterian missionaries based in Shanghai.
    - 14 circular and personal letters from the Lindholms primarily addressed to family of Paul's uncle, Arthur Woodruff, 1933-1940 (Box 374, Folder 2)
    - 5 photographs from bicycle trip to Soochow, biographical information, 1940, no date (Box 374, Folder 3)
  - Lindquist, Dorothy
    Biog. info: Taught English at Ginling College, Nanking (1922-1923)
    - Handwritten essays by Chinese women students at Ginling College, 1922-1923 (Box 321, Folder 1-13)
    - Handwritten Student worksheets (Box 321, Folder 14)
    - Typescript memoirs: "Christmas in China", "Memory of Confucius Tai Shan", "Nanking to Tianfu", 1922, 1923 (Box 321, Folder 15-16)
  - Little, Edward Selby
    Biog. info.: Methodist missionary 1890-1910 and founded the Kuling resort; was also in business and lived in New Zealand
    - Biographical information; photograph (Box 360, Folder 17)
    - Documentation re. the Kuling Estate resort and ESL, 1933, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 360, Folder 18)
  - Lo, Ruth Earnshaw
    Lived in China from 1937-1978; married to Lo Ch'uan-fang (John); taught at Huachung University
    - Typescript manuscript of book "The Life and Death of Hua Chung" - memoir of Lo's life in China and life at Huachung (Hua zhong da xue) Wuchang, Wuhan (468 pages) (Box 339, Folder 5-8)
  - Lobenstine, Edwin C.
    Biog. info: PN, YM Anhwei Prov., Shanghai (1898-1935)
    - Correspondence to friends of the Central Church, 1910 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to father, 1911 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence to Rose Lobenstine Beebe, 1919 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence to family, 1940 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Typescript report of E.C. Lobenstine to the meeting of Yale-in-China Association, 1940 (Box 119, Folder 7)
    - Typewritten and handwritten notes for sermon, 1933-1938 (Box 119, Folder 8-10)
    - Typewritten and handwritten notes for Address by E.C. Lobenstine: "The World Mission of Christianity", "Christianity in a Changing World", "The Significance of the F. Eastern Conflict", "Major Developments in China", "Our American Stake in China", "The Meeting of Protestant Christianity and Marxian Christianity in China", "How my Thinking on Protestantism Developed over the Years", etc, 1935-1951 (Box 119, Folder 11-20)
    - Typescript Material: President's and Chairman's remarks at meeting of Yale-in-China Association, 1941-1944 (Box 119, Folder 21-23)
    - Typescript Material: Biographical information re. E. C. Lobenstine, 1945-1958 (Box 119, Folder 24)
  - Lodwick, Kathleen
    Biog. info: Professor at Pennsylvania State University
    - Material related to Lodwick's project to produce indices to the Chinese Recorder. Includes biographical materials and references not available in published index. (1 of 10 boxes) (Box 283–292)
  - Logan Family
    Biog. info: Oliver Tracy Logan was an American Presbyterian medical missionary in Changteh, Hunan, China from 1898 until his death in 1919. His wife Jennie Manget Logan was a nurse who continued in medical work in China until 1938. Their daughter Elsa Logan returned to China as an adult as a missionary teacher.
    - "Little Stories of China" by Jennie Manget Logan, ca. 1943-1950 (Box 358, Folder 5)
    - "More Stories from China" - Dr. O. T. Logan, Jennie Manget Logan, Fred Manget (compiled by Nancy Logan), 1897-1979 (Box 358, Folder 6)
    - "Dear Friends - Letters from Elsa Logan, Teacher and Missionary, 1898-1988" edited by Nancy A. Logan, 1989 (Box 358, Folder 7)
    - Compilation of photographs with captions: printouts of scans from lantern slides. See International Mission Photography Archives for digital images. (Box 358, Folder 8)
    - Book: "Marshal Feng The Man and His Work"; letter from donor, 1926, 2004 (Box 358, Folder 9)
  - Lund, Hannah
    Biog. info: Sent as a missionary to China in 1897 by a Springfield, Massachusettes Swedish Covenant Church. She was killed in the Boxer Rebellion in the fall of 1900.
    - Photograph of Hannah Lund with three other missionaries: Beda Bjorkman, Mathilda Stromwall, Fred Anderson. Photograph of memorial plaque for Hannah Lund in Springfield, MA church (Box 359, Folder 1)
  - Lyons, Lucia E.
    - Circular letter, 1947 (Box 378, Folder 10)
  - McCallum, James H.
    - Typescript ms: "Account of the Japanese Atrocities at Nanking during the Winter of 1937-38", 1942 (Box 119, Folder 25)
  - McCandliss, Robert John
    PN medical missionary 1922-1942, stationed in Canton, Hwaiyuan, Anwhei
    - Bound volume: "Personal Reports and Published Letters of Medical Mission Activities in China" by Robert J. McCandliss; includes reports re. work at John G. Kerr Hospital for the Insane, Hope Hospital in Hwaiyuan, famine relief, 1928-1936, n.d. (Box 366, Folder 3)
    - Bound volume: "Japanese Invasion: Letters & Publicity 1937-1938; Hwaiyuan Anwhei China", includes personal correspondence and reports of McCandliss (Box 366, Folder 4)
    - Printed circular letters of McCandliss, 1932-1937 (Box 366, Folder 5)
    - Annual reports of Hwaiyuan Station, Kiangan Mission (1931-1932, 1932-1933, 1933-1934, 1938-1939); Annual report of mission work of Central Presbyterian Church, NY (1938); unidentified photograph, 1932-1938 (Box 366, Folder 6)
  - McClure, Jeanie Graham
    Biog. info: ABCFM, Fukien Prov. (1916-1937)
    - Biographical material, 1913-1971 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence to family, 1909-1918 (Box 120, Folder 2-12)
    - Correspondence to family, 1919-1928 (Box 121, Folder 1-12)
    - Photographs of Jeanie Graham McClure and her husband, 1916 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence to family and friends, 1929-1941 (Box 122, Folder 2-10)
    - Circular letters related to Foochow and Shaowu Missions of ABCFM, 1918-1932 (Box 122, Folder 11)
    - Printed Material related to Foochow and Shaowu Missions of ABCFM, 1905, 1915, 1934 (Box 122, Folder 12)
    - Diaries, 1917-1927, 1928-1937 (Box 122, Folder 13-14)
  - McCollough, Helen
    Biog. info: Niece of Elleroy and Maybelle Smith PN missionaries in Ningpo; spent a year in China with Smiths (1931-1932); taught English at girls' school near Ningpo
    - Correspondence: Letters to parents, 1931-1932 (Box 131, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence: Letters from others (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Collected Material: Magazines, articles, pictures, Art and poetry related to China and misc. memorabilia (Box 131, Folder 4-6)
    - Collected Items: books, Hankow Iteneraries, guest book, songs of Cathay (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Notes re. Chinese Symbolism and culture (Box 131, Folder 8-9)
    - Newspapers: North China Sunday News Magazine Nov 1931-Feb 1932; Diablo Beacon Calif. Sep 2, 1931, 1931-1932 (Box 131, Folder 10)
  - McCulloch, Gertrude F.
    Biog. info: ABFMS Hangchow, Chekiang, Shaohsing (1919-1949)
    - Summary statement of contents and statistics (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Shaohsing Mission Work incl. Shaohsing Hospital, nurses and staff; Waifs, orphans, Shaohsing Baptist leaders; Industrial help and labor relief, and others, 1940-1942 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - McCurdy, William A.
    Biog. info: MEFB Chungking, Nanking, Ginling College (1917-1951)
    - Correspondence to friends, 1932, 1939 (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - McCutcheon, James
    - Corres. re. JMcC's archival research in preparation of: "Preliminary Checklist on Unpublished Correspondence from American Protestant Missionaries in East and Southeast Asia to 1914" (1968-1969) (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - McFadyen, Archibald
    McFadyen (1877-1946) was a medical missionary serving under the Southern Presbyterian Mission from 1904 to 1942 in Hsuchowfu (Haichow) and Suchowfu (Suchow), Kiangsu (Jiangsu) province. McFadyen's first wife, Catherine, died in 1914. His second wife, Helen, was a nurse at the mission hospital in Suchowfu.
    - Letters from Archibald and Catherine McFadyen to his sister, from Davidson, North Carolina (1901) and Hsuchowfu, 1901, 1906-1909
    - Letters from Archibald and Catherine McFadyen to his mother and sister, from Hsuchowfu and Suchowfu, 1910-1916 (Box 374, Folder 5)
    - Letters from Archibald and Catherine McFadyen to his sister, from Hsuchowfu and Suchowfu, 1932, no date (Box 374, Folder 6)
    - Letters from Archibald to his wife Helen and daughter Sarah, 1935-1939 (Box 374, Folder 7)
    - Letters to/from others, including William Junkin, Letty Grafton, 1907-1908 (Box 374, Folder 8)
    - Letters to/from others, including cousin Flora Boyce, Sarah McFadyen from husband, 1925-1939, no date (Box 374, Folder 9)
  - McLean, Winfield A.
    Biog. info: ABCFM Peking, Fenchow (L.1924-L1927)
    - Correspondence, 1923-1924 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and report of Fenchow Hospital, 1925-1927 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - McLucas, Grace B.
    - Chinese clothing (Box OV7, Folder 1)
  - Macmillan, Eva B. A.
    Eva Macmillan was a Smith College graduate who served as an administrator at Peking Union Medical College.
    - Contents of notebook labeled "Eva B. A. Macmillan - 10 Year Career China" - includes notes and texts of talks given on various subjects about China, e.g., "A Home in Peking", "A Trip to a Chinese Temple", program of the Peking American College Women's Club, 1920s-1930s (Box 374, Folder 10)
  - McNeur, George and Margaret
    Biog. info.: George Hunter McNeur was the first missionary at the Canton Village Mission of the New Zealand Presbyterian Church in South China, established in 1902
    - Photograph album depicting scenes from Canton, including Union Theological College, Shung Kei Bible Training School, Pui Ying Middle School, True Light Middle School, Linchow, Canton Hospital, Lingnan University, Paak Hok Tung Refugee Centre, Hackett Medical Center, missionary families including Thomson, Brownell, Refo, Cadbury, McDonald, Laird, 1920-1939, n.d. (Box 359, Folder 2)
  - McVay, Frances Buckhout
    McVay was a graduate of Mount Holyoke College who served the ABCFM as a teacher from 1939 to 1943. She married a U.S. Navy Radioman, Harley Vilroy (H. Vilroy) McVay, in Foochow, on January 22, 1941 in the home of fellow missionary Willard Beard. home.
    - Correspondence, primarily to family from Foochow and Ingtai, 1939-07-26-1944-05-21 (Box 383, Folder 1-10)
    - Compiled booklet of transcribed letters and documents, prepared by Mary Ai-Li Kuntz: "A China Journey: Letters from China. Mary Frances Buckhout McVay, 1939-1943" (252 pages), 2014 (Box 383, Folder 11)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      A pdf version of this booklet is available at http://divinity-adhoc.library.yale.edu/Resources/China/Buckhout_McVay.pdf.
  - McWhirter, James
    McWhirter served under the London Missionary Society in Tientsin.
    - Letter from McWhirter to Frank Holland describes wartime conditions in China, 1946 (Box 374, Folder 11)
  - March, A. W.*
    Biog. info: PN Hangchow (1909-1950)
    - Handwritten "Diary of a Prisoner of War Under Japan, Dec. 8, 1941 to Sep. 19, 1942, China to Darrow", 1941-1942 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Marston, Miss Margaret (Mrs. Arthur M. Sherman)*
    Biog. info: ACM National Council Woman's Auxiliary New York City
    - Photographs of Anglican missionaries and clergy, 1935-1941 (Box 236, Folder 1)
    - Typescript letters from Alice Gregg, Anking, 1936-1937 (Box 236, Folder 2)
    - Typescript and handwritten letters and reports from members of Women's Missionary Service League of Chung Hua Sheng Kung Hui and indigenous Chinese clergy, 1936-1938, 1940, 1950 (Box 236, Folder 3)
    - Typescript and handwritten notes from meeting of Women's Missionary Service League of the Chinese Church, Wahu, 1934 (Box 236, Folder 4)
    - Typescript report: "Mrs. T.P.Yang's Trip to Shanghai", 1937 (Box 236, Folder 5)
    - Typescript report on Kiangsi Christian Rural Service Union by George Shepherd, 1936 (Box 236, Folder 6)
  - Martin, Emma Estelle (M.D.); Martin, Elizabeth Ellen*
    Biog. info: MEFB Peking, Tientsin, Shanghai Peking Union Med. College (1900-1925)
    - Photographs: People and scenes, 1902, 1920-1932 (Box 137, Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence: Letters to family, 1900-1923 (Box 137, Folder 4-12)
    - Letters to Girlies (Martin), Miss Emma Martin, 1900, 1908, 1912 (Box 137, Folder 13)
    - Misc: Menus, Pacific Mail Steamship Co., S.S. China, 1900 (Box 137, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper clippings concerning Dr. Emma and Lizzie Martin, 1900, 1911? (Box 137, Folder 15)
    - Diary written during siege of Peking by the Boxers, 1900 (Box 137, Folder 16)
      Digital copy available in Divinity Library AdHoc Digital Image and Text Database
  - Matthews, Alden
    Alden Matthews, son of Harold Matthews, served as a Congregational missionary in Fujian Province 1947-1950, including as Associate General Secretary of The Church of Christ in China Mid Fukien Synod.
    - Three circular letters of the Alden Matthews family, letter to "Friends of the Mid-Fukien Synod" with handwritten note from Matthews, 1948-1950 (Box 374, Folder 14)
  - Matthews, Harold*
    Biog. info: ABCFM Tehsien, Tientsin, Foochow (1922-1950)
    - Materials relating to Harold Matthews' 75 year (1860-1935) history of the ABCFM North China Mission (Box 138, Folder 1-4)
    - Materials relating to the history of the North China Mission of the ABCFM, 1935-1967 (Box 138, Folder 5-6)
    - Materials relating to UCBWM War Claim W-10378 Foochow Part I and II, 1937-1967 (Box 138, Folder 7-8)
    - Bound copy of book by HM: "Seventy-Five Years of the North China Mission" (ABCFM), 1942 (Box 138, Folder 9)
    - Typescript original ms. of above book, pp.1-132 with cover letter, 1935 (Box 138, Folder 10-11)
    - Typescript original ms. of above book, appendices, etc. (Box 138, Folder 12)
    - Typescript ms.: "The Foochow Mission of the American Board 1847-1951 incl. the Shaowu Mission 1918-1949", 1970 (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Typescript notes: "Some Historical Notes Concerning the North China Mission of the American Board", 1935-1960 (Box 139, Folder 2-4)
    - Printed mat. re. Harold Matthews' obituary, 1971 (Box 139, Folder 5)
  - Maupeu, Pierre
    Maupeu was a French Catholic missionary at the Trappist monastery of Notre Dame de la Consolation at Yangjiaping 1938-1940 and Notre Dame de Liesse at Zhengding 1940-1947.
    - Five letters to his parents in France describe Maupeu's voyage to China and wartime events., 1938-1939 (Box 374, Folder 12)
  - Mead, Frederica Rutherford
    Biog. info: PN Nanking: See also Lawrence Myers Mead Papers, RG 155
    - Correspondence to family, 1914-1920 (Box 140, Folder 1-4)
    - Letters to Frederica Rutherford Mead from others, 1918-1919 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - Letters to family from Lawrence Mead, 1919-1921 (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Lawrence Mead, 1894, 1915 (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - Typescript minutes, Board of Control, Ginling College, Nanking, 1915 (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - Typescript report: Personal report of Frederica R. Mead (Box 140, Folder 9)
    - Typescript essays: "A Pioneer Commencement", "Founder's day at Ginling College", etc., 1918, 1919 (Box 140, Folder 10)
    - Typed notice to Junior class, Nanking re. Course plan and program by the language School, Nanking Association, 1919 (Box 140, Folder 11)
    - Printed material: "The Source of Peace" by students of Ginling College, drama program, 1919 (Box 140, Folder 12)
  - Meebold, Louise
    - Circular letter from Fenyang, Shansi, 1949 (Box 309, Folder 7)
  - Merrell, Charlotte E.
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Chinese language material (Box 141, Folder 2)
  - Merwin, Wallace C.
    Biog. info: PN Paotingfu (L.1932-L.1940)
    - Photographs: "Nanking Theological Seminary, Board of Directors" and others, 1926, 1938, 1950 (Box 141, Folder 3)
  - Millican, Edith F.
    Biog. info: Dr. Edith Millican (1914-1985) was born in China of missionary parents. In 1943, she was asked by the Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions to work in China, since a doctor was badly needed at the mission hospital in Hengyang, Hunan. Dr. Millican served in China until 1948.
    - Printed material: "Where the Cranes Fly" The Adventures of Edith F. Millican in China, 1987 (Box 315, Folder 2)
  - Mills, Annetta Thompson
    Biog. info: Founder of the Chefoo School for the Deaf
    - Circular letter, 1924 (Box 309, Folder 6)
    - Printed mat.: "Sketch of the Life of Annetta Thompson Mills" by Anita E. Carter (Box 141, Folder 4)
  - Mills, Emily Ingersoll Case (Mrs. Samuel John Mills)*
    Biog. info: PN, Ginling College, Nanking
    - Photographs: Ginling College scenes, buildings, faculty and students, physical education activities, 1923-1939, 1981, 1982 (Box 266, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence, incl. re. experiences in Nanking, 1925-1927 (Box 266, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with family and memorabilia re. Ginling College, 1931-1932 (Box 266, Folder 5)
    - Typescript writings of ECM (Box 266, Folder 6)
    - Collected material, 1927 (Box 266, Folder 7-8)
    - Newspaper accounts of China situation, 1927 (Box 266, Folder 9-10)
    - Photographs: China scenes, buildings, individuals, groups, physical education and recreation activities, 1930-1934 (Box 267, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence: Personal corres. re. Ginling, 1936-1959, 1966-1972, 1973-1977 (Box 267, Folder 4-6)
    - Typescript ms.: Ginling memorabilia and tributes to former colleagues, 1933-1978 (Box 267, Folder 7)
    - Typescript material: Ginling Association in America - directories, newsletters, announcements, 1953-1955, 1956-1958, 1959-1961 (Box 267, Folder 8-10)
    - Typescript material: GAA - directories, etc, 1962-1982 (Box 268, Folder 1-3)
    - Typescript material: Ginling Girls' Middle School, Taiwan, 1959, 1966-1979 (Box 268, Folder 4)
    - Typescript material: "HongKong True Light Foundation", 1957-1979 (Box 268, Folder 5-7)
    - Rubber stamp of Ginling College (Box 268, Folder 8)
  - Mills, Samuel John*
    Biog. info: (1886-1970); PN Weihsien, Sung. Tengchow (1911-1933)
    - Photographs: Annetta Thompson Mills, Samuel Mills and others, 1899-1921 (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Typed ms: "Samuel J. Mills: The China Years, 1886-1933" (Box 141, Folder 6-10)
  - Mills, Wilson Plumer
    Biog. info: YMCA (1912-1932); PN (1932-1949) Nanking
    - Letters to family from 1938 Jan - Mar, when W. Plumer Mills remained in Nanking during the Rape of Nanking. Index and explanation of letters by daughter, Angie Mills; also. incl. letter of H. Maxcy Smith enclosing transcript of talk by John Rabe in Nanking 1938 Feb; typescript notes of M.S. Bates re. situation in Nanking (Box 141, Folder 11-17)
  - Minter, John and Elizabeth Minter
    Biog. info: PS Soochow
    - Letters to family, 1937 -1949 (Box 346, Folder 1-4)
    - Circular Letters, 1937-1949 (Box 346, Folder 5-6)
    - Letters to and from Chang Ye-joh, 1988-2005 (Box 346, Folder 7-10)
    - Letters to and from others, including Lindholm, Ming, Price, Taylor, Tsgi, Zhiyu (Box 346, Folder 11-12)